EDUCATION:

B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering from LKCE, Jalandhar affiliated to Punjab Technical University (2015 -2019)

12th Standard from DMS Jalandhar, affiliated to CBSE

10th Standard from DMS

Jalandhar, affiliated to CBSE

PROJECTS:

- Medpiper Landing website. (https://medpiper.com/)
- Savage web app. (https://www.savage.club/)
- Savage admin panel.
- Stolt-Nielsen landing website.
 (https://www.stolt-nielsen.com/)
- Form builder component.
- Service-now Dashboard (Power BI)

KEY DIFFERENTIATORS:

- Motivator
- Troubleshooter
- Team Player
- Intuitive
- Quick Learner
- Smart Worker

PARAS DUA

parasdua1997@gmail.com

+91 - 8568015594

EXECUTIVE PROFILE

Performing professional with 3+ years of experience into Front-end development with passion for coding and keeping up with the latest trends in software development and technology. Success in exceeding quality of service commitments and development of required solutions within defined timelines of business services. Skilled in process analysis & improvement, web application development consuming REST services. Developing applications in an agile way to fulfill the deadlines on time.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services Limited as Systems Engineer

June 2019 - December 2021

Web application development using React.js and Redux.

Mobcoder Technologies Pvt Ltd as SDE 2

December 2021 - Present

Web application development using React.is, Next.is and Redux.

Services and Operations:

- Requirement analysis, scoping, proof of concept, deployment and operations.
- Working closely with designers and engineers to build a compelling product
- Responsible for seamless UI development of Web Applications using React.js in Agile environment.
- Responsible for bringing in the improvements and new exciting functionalities in existing applications.
- Responsible for unit testing of each component developed using JEST.

SKILLS

JavaScript/TypeScript React.js/Next.js

Redux HTML5 CSS3 Git

SASS/SCSS TailwindCSS
Microfrontend AWS
Material UI JEST

KEY IMPACT AREAS

- Working with cross-functional teams.
- Responsive Web Development using React.is in Agile Environment.
- Unit Testing of each component developed using JEST.
- Launchina production-ready code.
- Changing code according to dynamic requirements of client.
- Promotion of the code to Production environment.